[Music]
I've been thinking a lot about borders
recently for no particular reason uh and
borders are a very innately human thing
if I don't have the right piece of paper
I cannot cross this Line in the Sand
like it's a very very real problem that
I face and many many people face every
single day and borders are just one kind
of constraints that humans just make up
and I think that's very interesting that
we respect borderers so much but AI does
not AI is a border disrespect it is very
very easily multilingual so if you
trained an LM on mostly mostly English
Text corpus it's going to learn other
languages just as a side effect it's
going to be very natively multimodal
because it can you can turn llama into a
vision language model with just like 100
bucks of just post training there's it's
very um disrespecting of ground trof
borders because it can just doesn't know
the difference between hallucination and
memorizing from a world model and it
also doesn't respect copyright which is
a whole other topic that we won't get
into today but it's also super
fascinating and how does that relate to
do with AI engineering right like I
think a lot of you here are here because
you are interested in that concept at
least maybe you identify as an AI
engineer maybe you're trying to hire an
AI
engineer so there a lot of definitions
floating around and I I confess that you
know I've I've contributed to that um is
the engineering an API line right that's
the that's the line that a lot of people
have and that's come under some debate
recently and yeah that that's one form
of AI engineering and I think that is
useful to some people for understanding
like where the responsibilities in a
team might stop an in and start with uh
the other people in the team or maybe
it's there different subtypes right like
last AI engineer Summit I talked about
the three types of AI engineer that I
was seeing emerge the AI enhanced
engineer the AI products engineer and
the non-human agentic AI
engineer or it could be a job
description that we try to sort of list
out and this is something that on the
Laten space podcast we recently went
through with elicit talking about the
different roles that they see within
their teams as well so okay if I broadly
have any of these three things do I have
I nailed down a good definition of
engineer that it's workable yes right
but is that something that we're happy
with is there something that we can is
is there nothing left to explore I think
the answer is no I think there's more to
explore I think the very easy copout as
well for people discussing this is that
you have your opinion I have my opinion
you come from your point of view I come
from my point of view we agree to
disagree or we agree that you know the
different different shs different folks
and we move on um I don't really like
that just because there's no shared
agreement on the things that is ground
truth to
everybody so I want to raise that
challenge a little bit more I was in a
podcast with razah Habib who's one of
the speakers today talking about what
this conference is and why this
conference is does what it does and I
always to say that a engineer
conferences are effectively my highest
Stakes expression of what I think the
state of a engineering is so this time
last year 2023 AI years are two times of
human years um uh we had a few tracks
and we had a few topics that were up for
debate we had rag Coen and then agents
and multimodality um all those tracks
are repeated here today I have some
speakers Illustrated here just for
illustrative purposes this obviously are
not every not everyone involved um but I
think just like the Inside Out metaphor
that uh I've been thinking a lot about
um as the AI engineer matures so does
the number of concerns that you have to
juggle in your head so this year you
know after you're a competent AI
engineer this year you're now faced with
like okay I have to migrate to open
models I have to build up my evals maybe
I should have done that first but that's
a whole topic of discussion maybe I
should scale up my inference or maybe I
should deploy it to the Fortune 500 and
maybe on the management side of things I
should be hiring teens of AI engineers
and managing AI strategy for my
company um I think think the last track
you know like I talking about the nine
tracks in in Engineers it's always about
the network the the community the
network that we're building um that's
probably the single most important part
of this conference and that's the part
that we cannot sell we cannot I cannot
put on the website hey we have a good
Community because no one will believe us
you have to C and see for yourself but
please for those of you who've been
uploading to the Google photos album
who've been tweeting out your photos uh
and sharing them and Linkedin please
keep doing that that's a way for myself
and everyone else who's not at the
conference to try to join in on the
fun um the the reason I'm not
comfortable with any of these tracks
because I is because I know how they
were made because I made them up and I
know that because I was looking at um
the the original document for the rise
of the AI engineer it's we're
celebrating the one- year anniversary
today and uh just down in the document
somewhere I just listed out the you know
disciplines that I thought the a
engineer would have and those eventually
became mostly mapping to the tracks that
I have been exploring in these
conferences and the meetups that I do
and it's arbitrary like why is there
separate agents track from Coden why is
there a separate rag track from open
models like these are all related um
what you know they're they're all of a
kind and obviously as an competent
engineer you should be familiar with all
these things and that brings us back to
this mindset of having boundaries and
borders right these are all made up by
someone I made them up for this one but
you know you're going to live in a world
where your boss made it up at your
company and these are not reflective of
how reality actually has to operate
right if if sted away all the rules and
a different group of people came in
would they agree on the same rules
probably not just because they're made
up but the laws of nature are hard to
make up because the reality actually
works that way if you had an alien
civilization come down to earth they
would discover that gravity works the
same the Sun the energy from the Sun
works the same the magnetic field works
the same so what are the laws of AI
engineering we we'll come we'll come to
that Thea definitions of software
engineering and real engineering so I
went and looked up definitions of
software engineering and i e talks about
the application of engineering to
software with the design implementation
testing and documentation of software
Google developers talks about mostly the
same thing they also mentioned software
life cycle management okay like really
reasonable definitions uh of a Kind
until you look at real Engineers real
Engineers talk about applying Natural
Science Sciences uh utilizing them for
benefit of
humanity both the I and National
Association of Engineers agree on that
uh and it's curiously missing from
software engineering like the benefiting
Humanity part the understanding natural
laws part completely missing from
software engineering so my proposal to
you is that AI engineering is somewhere
in between right the the the the the
software engineering but then
encountering a lot of the more of the
real world constraints than you would in
a typical software engineer
career so if we know the laws of Earth
and they are independently derived they
cannot no matter what point of view
you're looking at they all are the same
laws then what are the equivalent laws
of AI engineering I have a few you can
come up with more but I'm just going to
propose some to start off
debate there's constants so for example
if you're designing for humans you
should respect the fact that humans only
speak at 80 words per minute but they
read at 200 words per minute right so
there's an inherent disparity there
there's also con contingent facts that
things that are true for now instead of
true forever and true for now facts are
for example like the Apple intelligence
when they ship a local model on every
phone then that inference speed of 30
tokens per second that they're
advertising becomes the Baseline speed
limit or speed barrier of what
intelligence that is too cheap to meter
should look like and these things
they're not set in stone they're not
actual physical laws so they also Trend
over time due to forces and momentum and
I want to establish a little bit like I
think it's it's very beneficial for AI
Engineers to understand what the Moors
laws of AI is so that you can plan for
them so that you don't have to make the
bad bets that are not going to last just
obviously just because of overwhelming
evidence the first bet is the improving
of context right um a year ago I was
interviewing Mosaic and talking about MP
c7b with they're whopping 60,000 70,000
token context with a lot of loss today
sitting in the audience we have people
who have trained million token context
windows and we've also uh have from
anthropic which just released Cloud 35
yester last week um that the fact that
you know we have complete utilization
it's not just about the length of
context it's also about the utilization
of context and I think Greg who setting
the audience as well would be very happy
with how cloud is improving on their
utilization of their very very long
context Windows there's Al the cost of
intelligence the commodification of
intelligence so in the past two years
we've seen a
99.55% decline in the cost of gpt3 level
intelligence the cost of GT4 level
intelligence has probably come down
maybe 90% maybe maybe 80% um from from
GT4 to Lama 3 and all the the newer
models that finally I think it's worth
commenting a little bit on where AI
engineering stands in contrast to other
AI philosophies there's EA versus eak
and maybe we're in the middle like we we
care about safety but we also want to
accelerate right right it's kind of like
a weird combination of of the two things
my proposal is that that one dimension
isn't enough to express how a engineer
differs from the other philosophies and
actually need to add a second dimension
to talk about utility we are utility
Maxis above all else we see what's out
there and we want to use it to benefit
Humanity so my message to everyone at
the world fair is to try to disrespect
borders a little bit try to avoid your
own dogmatic beliefs lazy consensus of
other people or passive reactions and in
other words try to disagree disagree
more disagree with your own conclusions
disagree with each other productively
and disagree with the status quo and I
think there you'll find that this
conference becomes more of a useful
landmark in your careers rather than
just the party which it can very well be
uh but my final analogy which I really
like is that AI Engineers are the kind
of person that looks at shov and sees
instead of a monster that cannot be
tamed they want to turn them into Mass
Rapid Transit and the kind of person
that looks at that looks at you know
force of Nature and wants to turn it
into tools that are useful for people is
the kind of engineer that I would love
to speak to and welcome at conferences
like this one so that's my view of what
borders and Engineering Without Borders
should look like I I very much encourage
you to jump between tracks to jump
between friend groups to jump between
disciplines and modalities because
here's the one place that you can do
that outside of your work um and to
mingle with everyone else that we've
gathered so I hope you enjoy doing that
um I wish I was there in person but just
share them online and I hope to see you
in person in at the next one bye
[Music]